Inventory of the Soviet and post-Soviet independent publications collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Soviet and post-Soviet independent publications collection
1986-2006
2012C30
108 manuscript boxes, 461 oversize boxes (237 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Serial issues, relating to political, social and economic conditions in Russia.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in increments between 1986 and 2012.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks. stanford. edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
From 1987 to the present, the Hoover Institution has been amassing the political opposition press from Russia, Belarus, Ukraine, and other parts of the former Soviet Union. From 1987 to 1991, the opposition consisted of the "democrats"; since 1991 it has consisted of Communists and others on the left as well as the national patriotic groups and fascists on the right. Today the political opposition press collection is composed of over 4,800 serial titles.
Arranged in alphabetical order.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by title.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Soviet Union--Politics and government--1985-1991.; Soviet Union--Economic conditions--1985-1991.; Soviet Union--Social conditions--1970-1991.; Russia (Federation)--Politics and government--1991-; Russia (Federation)--Economic conditions--1991-; Russia (Federation)--Social conditions--1991-
Collection Contents
- Key: TITLE Subtitle. Publisher. Editor. Publication location. Publication frequency. Publication Start date, Sorted by year
- III-ii RIM vestnik Rossiiskogo patrioticheskogo dvizheniia. Redaktory: M. Artem'ev, V. Rugich. Moscow, Russia. 1989-, one undated issue no. 3 with headline "Narodnye li?" 1989: no. 1-3 1991: no. 5, no. 7-81994: no. 11997: no. 2 (Box 460)
- VII LINNIIA the seventh line. Gl. redaktor: M. Rozenberg. S. -Peterburg, Russia. 19??-, 1992: no. 2 1993: no. 2, no. 4 (Box 460)
- XXI VEK respublikanskaia ezhenedel'naia obshchestvenno-politicheskaia gazeta. Glavnyi redaktor: Bigel'dy Gabdullin. Almaty, Kazakhstan. Weekly. 1998-, 1998: no. 23-26, no. 29 1999: no. 1(43), no. 3(45), one unnumbered and undated issue with headline, "Ia govoriu Vlasti: "Net!"," no. 34(76), no. 42(84)-43(85)2000: no. 16(107), no. 20(111), no. 22(113)-23(114) (Box 1)
- 12 See: Dvenadtsat'.
- 1-i SIBIRSKII FRONT Tomsk, Russia. 2003?-, 2003: One unnumbered issue with headline "K sibiriakam!." (Box 1)
- 19 IANVARIA gazeta Orekhovo-zuevskoi organizatsii Kommunisticheskoi partii Rossiiskoi Federatsii. Otvetstvennyi za vypusk: V. I. Khromov. Orekhovo-Zuevo, Russia. 1995-, 1997: April (Box 1)
- 24 mezhdunarodnaia gazeta. Gl. redaktor: Iu. Zarechkin. Moscow, Russia. Semiweekly. 199?-, 1992: June 2, June 9, no. 41, no. 53, no. 55, no. 58-60, no. 62-67, no. 69-71, no. 73 1993: no. 1(74)-6(79), no. 8(81)-9(82), no. 11(84)-14(87), no. 16(89), no. 19(92)-23(96), no. 25(98)-37(110), no. 38(111)-42(115), no. 44(117)-48(121), no. 50(123), no. 56(129), no. 59(132)-60(133), no. 62(135), no. 66(139), no. 76(149) (Box 1)
- 30 OKTIABRIA Uchrediteli: Mezhdunarodnoe istoriko-prosvetitel'skoe, blagotvoritel'noe i pravozashchitnoe obshchestvo "Memorial," Istoriko-prosvetitel'skoe, blagotvoritel'noe i pravozashchitnoe obshchestvo "Moskovskii Memorial," Moskovskoe ob''edinenie lits, postradavshikh ot politicheskikh repressii. Glavnyi redaktor: G. C. Shvedov. Moscow, Russia. Approx. monthly. 2000?-, 1999: no. 1-2 2000: no. 3-11 2001: no. 12-20 2002: no. 21-28 2004: no. 45 2006: no. 632009: no. 91-92 (Box 2)
- 4 OKTIABRIA gazeta zashchitnikov Doma Sovetov. Prilozhenie k gazete "Obnovlenie." Elektrostal', Russia. 199?-, 1997: no. 1 1998: no. 2 1999: no. 3-4 (Box 2)
- 41 gazeta Zelenograda. Gl. redaktor: S. Chernykh. Moscow, Russia. 1990-, 1990: no. 22(27) 1992: no. 6, no. 20(63), no. 41(84), no. 45/46(88/89)1993: no. 5(102), no. 28(125) (Box 2)
- 451 PO FARENGEITU nezavisimaia obshestvenno-politicheskaia ezhenedel'naia gazeta. Glavnyi redaktor: Iurii Mizinov. Almaty, Kazakhstan. Weekly?. 19??-, 1998: no. 3(35) (Fall), no. 11(44) (11980) (Winter), no. 12(45) (11981) (Winter) 1999: no. 1(13) (11982) (Spring), no. 2(!4) (11983) (Spring) (Box 3)
- 58-ia - ZHERTVY I PALACHI organ Vsesoiuznoi Assotsiatsii zhertv politicheskikh repressii. Subtitle varies: 1995 no. 5/6(28/29)- "organ Mezhdunarodnoi Federatsii i Rossiiskoi Assotsiatsii zhertv politicheskikh repressii," 1996 no. 8/9- "gazeta sotsial'noi zashchity" Redaktory: M. Malinin, Iurii Durnev. Moscow, Russia. 19??-, 1991: January 10 1993: no. 1(6)-4(9), no. 6(11), March (Special issue titled "Obrashchenie, initsiativnoi gruppy po provedeniiu...")1994: no. 1(12), no. 8/9(19/20)-12(23) 1995: no. 1(24)-12(36) (Box 3)
- 60 MINUT Daidzhest "glasnost'." Redaktor: Aleksei Sheinin. Riga, Latvia. 19??-, 1990: One unnumbered issue with headline, "Evoliutsiia leninskogo, uravneniia." (Box 460)
- 7 DNEI Redaktor: A. Prianishnikov. Minsk, Byelorussia. Weekly. 19??-, 1991: no. 21(73) 1992: no. 24/25(128/129), no. 43(147)1993: no. 1(157)-52(208) (Box 3)
- 24 Chasa Obozrenie otechestvennoi I zarubezhnoi pressy. Oleg Petrichenko. St. Peterburg, Russia. Weekly?., 1993: no. 35-38 (Box 3)
- 88 Informtsentr Armianskogo obshchenatsional'nogo dvizheniia. Redaktor: A. Areumanian. Erevan, Armenia. 1990-, 1990: no. 2-5 (Box 460)
- 999 informatsionnyi vestnik; istochnik nezavisimoi informatsii. Izdanie Demokraticheskikh sil Bolgradskogo raione. Bolgrad, Ukraine. 19??-, 1990: no. 3-5 (Box 460)
- A & R Al'ternativa "Reporter" - sovmestnyi vypusk. Redaktor: Svalov, S. (Reporter); Nyrko, V. (Al'ternativa). Iaroslavl', RSFSR. 19??-, 1991: May 15 - June 15 (Box 4)
- A & S INFO See: A-S Info.
- A B S PANORAMA zhurnal (Fenzin) po voprosam tvorchestva brat'ev Strugatskikh. Lia "Obersan" Gl. redaktor: Kazakov, V. Iu. Saratov, RSFSR. 1989?-, 1989: no. 3 (Box 460)
- A i B annotirovannyi informatsionnyi biulleten'. Organ Moskovskoi sektsiiSotsialisticheskoi partii. Moscow, Russia. 1991?-, 1991: no. 3-4, spetsvypusk, no. 6 (Box 460)
- A INFO [s. l.: s. n. ]. 199?-, 1993: May/June/July/August (Box 460)
- A N - PRESS See: Biulleten' AN-Press.
- A N I See: Agenstvo Novostei i Informatsii.
- A T V (Al'ternativnyi Tvorcheskii Vestnik) ezhenedel'naia gazeta. Gl. redaktor: Sokolovskii, V. Khar'kov, Russia. 19??-, 1991: no. 51 1992: no. 10(63) (Box 4)
- ABKHAZIIA Nezavisimaia gazeta. Moskovskii vypusk. Glavnyi redaktor: T. L. Arshba. Moscow, Russia. 1990-, 1994: no. 1(79)-2(80) 1995: no. 1(82)-2(83), no. 4(85)1996: no. 5(86) (Box 4)
- ABKHAZSKII VESTNK Moskovskoe obshchestvo Abkhazskoi kul'tury "Nartaa." Redaktor: Anchabadze, Iu. D. Moscow, Russia. Monthly?. 1993-, 1993: no. 1(1)-3(3) 1994: no. 1(4) (Box 4)
- ABUDZHEN'NE ves'nik Mahileuskai rady Belaruskaha narodnaha frontu. Minsk, Byelorussia. 1989-, 1989: no. 1-2 1990: no. 2(4) (Box 460)
- ACHYG SOZ mustagiia press-bulleten. Redaktor: Akhmedov, E. Baku, Azerbaijan. 1989-, 1989? no. 1-4 (Box 460)
- ACTIVITATEA SOCIALISTA "Sotsialisticheskoe deistvie" - gruppa moldavskikh storonnikov komiteta za rabochii Internatsional. Moscow, Russia?., one unnumbered and undated issue, with lead article titled "Moldova. Zhizn' posle zhizni" (Box 4)
- ADAEMY KH''AELAES / GOLOS NARODA gazeta kommunisticheskoi partii trudiashchikhsia severnoi Osetii. Vladikavkaz, Russia. 1992-, 1993: no. 3(7), no. 6(10) 1994: no. 1(12) (Box 4)
- ADAMALLA CHELOVECHNOST' organ obshchestvenno-politicheskogo dvizheniia "Adamalla - Chelovechnost'." Uchreditel': Obshchestvenno-politicheskoe dvizhenie "Za natsional'noe vozrozhdenie Chechenskogo naroda i Chechenskoi Respubliki "Adamalla - Chelovechnost'."" Redaktory: S. M. Abdurashidov, A. A. Zubairaev. Moscow, Russia. 199?-, 1999: no. 1 2000: one unnumbered issue dated January with headline "Dorogie sootechestvenniki!," one unnumbered issue date April with headline "Mir i poriadok..." (Box 4)
- ADAMON NYKHAS "Narodnoe Sobranie." Vestnik Narodnogo fronta iuzhnoi Osetii. (Russian language edition). Tskhinvali, Georgia. Monthly. 198?-, 1989: no. 1 (Box 460)
- ADYGEISKAIA PRAVDA gazeta Adygeiskogo respublikanskogo otdeleniia Kommunisticheskoi partii Rossiiskoi Federatsii. Redaktor: V. S. Zaitsev. Maikop, Adygeiia. 2 issues per month. 1993-, 2005: no. 12(292), no. 17(297) (Box 4)
- AG"ULARIN KHABARAR respublikanskaia obshchetvenno-politicheskaia gazeta. Gl. redaktor: A. Maiafov. Dagestan. Weekly. 19??-, 1998: no. 3/4(5286-5287)-5/6(5286-5287) (Box 4)
- AGENSTVO NOVOSTI I INFORMATSII Redaktory: Maksim Demidov, Anatolii Papp. [Moscow, Russia. ]. 19??-, 1991: no. 15 (Box 460)
- AGENTSTVO SOTSIAL'NO-POLITICHESKOI INFORMATSII Redaktory: V. Berlader, M. Komarova, D. Fedorov. Moscow, Russia. Approx. monthly. 1994?-, 1994: no. 2-4 1995: no. 2(9)-3(10)1996: no. 2(20)-7(25) 1997: no. 1(26)-3(28), no. 5(30)-7(32)1998: no. 1(33)-9(41) 1999: no. 1(42)-3(44) (Box 460)
- AGITATSIONNAIA LISTOVKA Redaktsionnaia kollegiia: T. G. Avaliani, R. Kuliev, E. B. Sakhon'ko, N. N. Sergeev. Moscow, Russia. 199?-, 1999: one unnumbered issue with headline "VTsBK: rabochii proryv" (Box 4)
- AGRARNAIA REFORMA V ROSSII press-biulleten' dlia federal'nykh, oblastnykh i raionnykh sredstv massovoi informatsii. [s. l.: s. n. ]. 1995-, 1995: no. 1 (October) (Box 460)
- AHRO informatsiino-reklamna hazeta. Ivano-Frankivs'ka Obl., Ukraine. 19??-, 1990: no. 19 1991: no. 44(220) (Box 4)
- AISBERG prilozhenie k press-biulleteniu "Svoboda mnenii." See also: Svoboda mnenii Redaktor: Vinogradov, G. Leningrad, Russia. 19??-, 1990: no. 1-3 (Box 4)
- AKHINA WELAT [= Ston Rodiny] Uchreditel': Kurdskaia natsional'no-kul'turnaia avtonomiia g. Moskvy. Redaktor: Korda Mad. Moscow, Russia. Monthly. 1998?-, 2001: no. 9(134)-10(135), no. 12(137) 2002: no. 1(138) (Box 4)
- AKMATOVSKII VESTNIK literaturnyi vypusk «Russkogo Vestnika». Redaktor: Mikhail Bogustov. Valka, Latvia. 1989-, 1990: no. 2(3) (Box 4)
- AKTSIIA gazeta dlia dumaiushchei molodezhi. Glavyni redaktor: Svetlana Maksimchenko. Moscow, Russia. 2001-, 2002: no. 6(13) (Box 4)
- AKTUAL'NAIA INFORMATSIIA vserossiiskii obshchestvenno-politicheskii ezhenedel'nik. Glavnyi redaktor: Vadim Bondar'. Moscow, Russia. Weekly. 2000?-, 2001: no. 6(10) (June) (Box 4)
- AKTUAL'NAIA TEMA Obshchestvenno-politicheskii tsentr MGK i MK KPSS. Otv. za vypusk: Ermachenko, A. Moscow, Russia. 19??-, 1991: no. 12, no. 14 (Box 460)
- ALANTAE Redaktor: Akhwhar Tulaev. Vladikavkaz, Russia. 1994-, 1997: no. 14 (Box 4)
- ALASHARA vestnik Moskovskogo obshchestva Abkhazskoi kul'tury "Nartaa." Otv. redaktor: Chirikba, V. Moscow, Russia. 1989-, 1989: no. 1 (Dec. 30) 1990: no. 1(2)-2(3) (Jan. -Feb. ) (Box 4)
- ALEKS-INFORM Russkaia natsional-patrioticheskaia gazeta. Redaktor: O. Kitter. Samara, Russia. 24 issues per year. 1998?-, 1999: no. 6(17), no. 8(19), no. 10(21), no. 16(27), no. 17(29)-21(32), no. 23(34)-24(35) 2000: no. 1(60)-2(61), no. 5(64), no. 8(67)-9(68), no. 12(71)-13(72), no. 15(74)-19(78), no. 21(80)-24(83)2001: no. 3(86)-5(88), no. 7(90)-12(95), no. 13(95) [sic], no. 14(95) [sic], no. 15(96)-23(104) 2002: no. 1(105)-4(108)2003: no. 10(137), no. 22(149) 2004: no. 1(152)-2(253) (Box 6)
- AL'-FIKR See: Mysl' = Al'-fikr.
- AL'-KODS Mezhdunarodnaia kul'turno-prosvetitel'skai gazeta. Palestinskii golos, zateriannyi v Rossii. Subtitle varies: 1995 no. 1(56) "Russko-Palestinskii golos"Izdatel' gazety - doktor Shaaban Khafiz. Moscow, Russia. 2 issues per month. 19??-, 1992: no. 10/34, no. 36, no. 38(3), no. 40(4)-42(6) 1993: no. 1/2(7/8)-15(21)1994: no. 16(22), no. 2(23)-6(27), no. 8(29)-21(42), no. 24(45)-33(54) 1995: no. 1(56)-12(67)1996: no. 1(68)-2(69) (Box 5-6)
- ALLO literaturnye opyty. Redaktor: Makarova-Naumova, D. Leningrad, Russia. 1990-, 1990: no. 2 1991: no. 1(3)-4(6)1992: no. 1(7)-2(8), no. 4(10)-5(11) (Box 6)
- ALMA MATER studencheskaia gazeta. Redaktor: Kuzovkin, D. Tartu, Estonia. 1990-, 1990: no. 1-2 (Mar. -Apr. ), no. 1(3)-2(4) (Sept. -Oct. ) 1991: January - spetsial'nyi vypusk, no. 2(4)-3(5) (Box 6)
- AL'MANAKH vestnik Litovskogo dvizheniia za perestroiku "Sajudis." Vestnik LDP. Redaktor: Kozailis, A. Vilnius, Lithuania. 1988-, 198? one unnumbered and undated issue with lead article titled "Tainye dokumenty..." 198? no. 4 (undated) "spetsvypusk" 1988: no. 10 (September), no. 12 (October) (Box 460)
- AL'TERNATIVA (Kiev) gazeta ob'edinennykh sotsial-demokratov Gl. redaktor S. Grabovskii. Kiev, Ukraine. 1996, 1998: spetsvypusk (Box 458)
- AL'TERNATIVA (Leningrad) organ Svobodnoi demokraticheskoi partii. Redkollegiia: Svetova, L., El'kin, G. Leningrad, Russia. 19??-, 19??: one unnumbered and undated issue (2 p. ) (Box 7)
- AL'TERNATIVA (L'vov) ezhenedel'nik informtsentra USSDA. Otvetstvennyi za vypusk: Red'ko, D. L'vov, Ukraine. 1990?-, 1990: no. 3 (Box 460)
- AL'TERNATIVA (Minsk) Organ Sotsial-demokraticheskogo soiuza. Has supplement: Glasnost' See also: Glasnost' (Minsk) Gl. redaktor: Berezin, V. A. Minsk, Byelorussia. 1989-, 1989: no. 1 (September), no. 2 (October), no. 3 (December) 1990: no. 4 (April) (Box 460)
- AL'TERNATIVA (Moscow) mezhregional'nyi sotsial-demokraticheskii vestnik. Sotsial demokraticheskaia assotsiatsiia; Sotsial-demokraticheskaia partiia Rossiiskoi federatsii. Redaktor: Nyrko, V. M. Moscow, Russia. Monthly. 1990-, 1990: July, no. 1-4 1991: no. 5-7, no. 9-10, no. 12-141992: no. 1(15)-4(18), no. 6(20)-26 1993: no. 1(27)-2(28), no. 29-31, no. 33-35 (Box 7)
- AL'TERNATIVA (Murmansk) Murmanskii oblastnoi Soiuz kooperativov. Redaktor: Valamina, Iu. Murmansk, RSFSR., 1990: September (Box 7)
- AL'TERNATIVA (Perm') Demokraticheskii soiuz. Redaktor: Bychenkov, S. I. Perm', RSFSR. 1989-, 1989: no. 2 (September) (Box 460)
- AL'TERNATIVA (Ternopol') hazeta Ternopil's'koi orhanizatsii partii demokratychnoho vidrodzhennia Ukrainy. Ternopol', Ukraine. Semimonthly. 1991-, 1991: no. 2 (Box 7)
- AL'TERNATIVA (Tver') politicheskaia gazeta. Redaktsiia: M. Galaida, D. Gevarin, N. Vikhrev, V. Vladimirov, Ia. Sapatin. Tver', Russia. Approx. 6 issues per year. 1991-, 2004: no. 2 2005: no. 3-6, no. 82006: no. 9 (Box 460)
- AL'TERNATIVA (Vilnius) nezavisimaia gazeta poselok Snechkus; prilozhenie k gazeta "Soglasie." Demokraticheskii klub poselka Snechkus; Atgimimas (tovarishchestvo). See also: Soglasie Redaktor: Zhdanova, R. Vilnius, Lithuania. Semimonthly. 1990?-, 1991: no. 5(17), no. 7(19)-9(21) (Box 7)
- AL'TERNATIVA KPSS Partiia Demokraticheskii soiuz. [s. l.: s. n. ]. 19??-, 19?? one unnumbered and undated issue (18 p. ) (Box 460)
- AL'TERNATIVNYI TVORCHESKII VESTNIK See: A T V. (Box 7)
- AL'TERNATIVY Mezhdunarodnyi obshchestvenno-politicheskii i analiticheskii zhurnal. Redaktor: A. Buzgalin. Moscow, Russia. Semiannual. 1991-, 1991: no. 1 1993: no. 31994: no. 1(4)-2(5) 1995: no. 1-31996: no. 2-3 1996/97: no. 4 1997: no. 2-3 1998: no. 1-2 1999: no. 2-4 2000: no. 1-4 2001: no. 1, no. 4 2002: no. 3-4 2005: no. 3 (Box 461-462)
- AL'TERNATYVA shchotyzhnevyk L'vivs'koi Sotsial-demokratychnoi orhanizatsii. L'vov, Ukraine. 19??-, 1990: no. 1 (Box 462)
- AMBRAZURA listok Leningradskoi organizatsii revoliutsionnogo komsomola - RKSM(B). [Sankt-Peterburg, Russia. ]. 2002?-, 2002? nos. 4,7 (Box 462)
- AMFITEATR ezhenedel'naia gazeta. Otv. redaktor: Maisurian, A. Moscow, Russia. Weekly. 19??-, 1992: no. 1-3 (Box 7)
- AMI = NAROD MOI See: Narod Moi.
- AMVON pravoslavnyi zhurnal v pomoshch' katekhizatoru i missioneru. Redaktor: Vershillo, P. A. Moscow, Russia. 198?-, 198?: no. 1, no. 3 (Box 7)
- ANARKHICHESKII VESTNIK gazeta Regional'nogo Obshchestvennogo Dvizheniia "Anarkhicheskii Al'ians." Uchreditel': Dvizhenie "Anarkhicheskii Al'ians" i proekt "Avtonomnoe Deistvie"Glanyi redaktor: S. Nikiforov. Moscow, Russia. 1999?-, 1999: no. 2 (June-August), no. 3 (September-October) 2000: no. 4 (January-March), no. 5 (April-October), no. 6 (November 2000 - May 2001) (Box 462)
- ANARKHIIA (Donetsk) Sotsial'no-revoliutsionnoe obozrenie. Federatsii Anarkhistov Donbassa. Konfederatsiia anarkho-sindikalistov. Redaktor: M. Volin. Donetsk, Ukraine. 1993-, 1993: unnumbered issue 1996: no. 1(2) (Box 7)
- ANARKHIIA (Gomel') Gomel'skaia organizatsiia Federatsii Anarkhistov Belarusi. Redaktsionnaia kollegiia: V. Loginov, Iu. Glushakov, V. E. Pashuk. Gomel', Byelorussia. 1993-, 1993: no. 1 (undated issue), "Osen'" (unnumbered issue) 1994: "Osen'"1995: no. 1(3), no. 1(13) (Box 7)
- ANARKHIIA (Leningrad) izdanie Petrogradskoi sektsii Konfederatsii Anarkho- sindikalistov. Redaktor: Mikhailov, A. Leningrad, Russia. 1990?-, 1990: no. 1 1991: no. 2 (Box 462)
- ANARKHIIA (Nizhni Novgorod) nezavisimyi zhurnal radikal'nogo dvizheniia "Khraniteli Radugi." See also: Tretii Put'Otvetstvennye redaktory: Nadezhda Shevchenko, Sergei Fomichev. Nizhnii Novgorod, Russia. 1997?-, 1997? no. 1 (undated) (Box 462)
- ANARKHIST Tul'skii soiuz anarkhistov. Note: possibly related to Tula Anarkhist. [Tula, Russia. ]. 19??-, 1994: no. 1(12) (April) (Box 462)
- ANDREEVSKII FLAG - 300 mezhregional'nyi morskoi informatsionno-istoricheskii vestnik. Redaktory: Korzhov, S., Taneeva, I. K. S. -Peterburg, Russia. 1992-, 1992: no. 1-10/12 1993: no. 1/4(1316)1994: no. 1(4) joint issue with "Soiuz Ofitserov" (unnumbered)., no. 2(5) 1997: no. 1 (as listed on front page, but has September date and maybe no. 11. ), no. 12 December1998: no. 7, spetsvypusk (11th Aug. ) (Box 7)
- ANDRIIVSKYI UZVIZ iliustrovanyi tyzhnevyk. Vydannia derzhavnogo istoryko- arkhitekturnoho zapovidnyka "Starodavnii Kyiv." Forum (press klub). Holovnyi redaktor: Sharkov, V. Kiev, Ukraine. 1990?-, 1991: no. 1, no. 5 1992: no. 4(9) (Box 7)
- ANDROPOVSKAIA PRAVDA regional'naia gazeta trudiashchikhsia. Redaktor: Tkalenko, A. Murmansk, RSFSR. 1991-, 1992: no. 4-10 1993: no. 1(11)-6(16), no. 7(17) (Box 7)
- ANEKDOT pechatnyi organ Menskogo kluba liubitelei anekdotov imeni Shtandartenfiurera SS Shtirlitsa. Glavnyi redaktor: A. Romashevskii. Minsk, Belarus'. 1990-, 1990: no. 1 (Box 462)
- ANICHKOV MOST Sovet narodnykh deputatov, Kuibyshevskii raion; Nevskii prospekt (fond). Gl. redaktor: Tatarnikova, V. E. Leningrad, Russia. Weekly. 1990?-, 1991: no. 2-3 (January), no. 6, no. 10, no. 12, no. 14, no. 20, no. 25, no. 35-52 1992: no. 1(53)-14, no. 16-18(69), no. 20(71)-25(76)1993: no. 1(86), no. 3(88), no. 5(90)-6/7(92/93), no. 9(94)-10(95), no. 15(100), no. 17(102) 1994: no. 5(107) (Box 8)
- AN-PRESS biulleten'. See: Biulleten' An-Press.
- AN-PRESS DIGEST review of Russian anarchic movement. See also: Biulleten' An-PressEditor: Geskin, P. S. -Peterburg, Russia. 19??-, 199?: no. 1 (December 1992 - March 1993) (Box 8)
- ANIEM-MAMA gazeta respublikanskogo blagotvoritel'nogo fonda "Aniem"-"Mama"Shef-redaktor Kh. Gainullin. Kazan, Russia., 1999: no. 1 (Box 459)
- ANTI GAZETA See: Moment istiny.
- ANTIFASHISTSKII MOTIF Continues: Tum-balalaiki. (Sankt-Peterburg). 2002-, 2002: no. 1-3 2005: no. 5 2006: no. 6-7 (Box 462, 564)
- ANTIGLOBALISTSKAIA KUVALDA gazeta antiglobalistskogo patrioticheskogo soiuza molodezhi. Redaktor: Mikhail Kuznetsov. Sankt-Peterburg, Russia. 2003-, 2003? no. 3-4, one unnumbered issue with headline, "Ka-a-ak ebnem!" (Box 462)
- ANTIMAFIIA gazeta protivodeistviia organizovannoi prestupnosti i korruptsii. Glavnyi redaktor: Ovcharenko, G. S. Moscow, Russia. 1992(?)-, 1992: no. 0 (April) (Box 8)
- ANTIMILITARIST biulleten' Antimilitaristskoi Radikal'noi Assotsiatsii (ARA). Otvetstvennyi redaktor: Nikolai Khramov. Moscow, Russia. 199?-, 1995: no. 0 1996: no. 21997: no. 3-5, no. 7 1998: no. 1-31999: "spetsial'nyi vypusk 15 marta..." (Box 462)
- ANTISEMITIZM I KSENOFOBIIA V ROSSIISKOI FEDERATSII Informationno-analiticheskii biulleten'., 2001: no. 10 (Box 462)
- ANTISOVETSKAIA PRAVDA organ Respublikanskoi partii. See also: Anti-Soviet pravda, Na Razval Imperii! Redaktor: Bogdanov, A. Leningrad, Russia. 198?-, 1989: no. 1 (?) with headline "Kak El'tsin Sbezhal...," no. 2 (?) with headline "Dorogaia Raisa...," no. 3 (October), Oct. 26 issue with headline "Krakh Egora...", no. 3 (November), "ekstrennyi vypusk" with headline, "raskryto glavnoe perstuplenie?," no. 6, no. 7 with headline "Tovarishch Bush!" (December), no. 7 with headline "Dikie gusi...," no. 8 with headline at bottom of page "KGB rabotaet...," no. 8 with headline "Chto my zhdem...," no. 9, "ekstrennyi vypusk" with headline "Pesnia o Bore..." 1990: no. 10, undated issue with headline "Programma - minimum," no. 12, no. 15, no. 17-18, no. 20-28, one unnumbered issue with headline "Zadachi novoi revoliutsii...," no. 29-30, unnumbered issue with headline "Da zdravstvuet velikaia...," no. 33-34 (Box 462)
- ANTISOVETSKII KHAR'KOV izdanie partii Demokraticheskii Soiuz. Redaktor: Levin, E. Khar'kov, Ukraine. 19??-, 1991: no. 1-2 1992: no. 3-4, no. 6 (Box 8)
- ANTISOVETSKII KRIVBASS gazeta Krivorozhskoi organizatsii partii "Demokraticheskii Soiuz." Redaktor: Danilov, V. Moscow, Russia. 1991?-, 1991: no. 1-2 (Box 8)
- ANTI-SOVIET PRAVDA See also: Antisovetskaia pravda Gl. redaktor: Bogdanov, A. S. -Peterburg, Russia. 19??-, 1990? no. 35 (Box 462)
- ANTITEZA gazeta profsoiuza remonto-stroitel'nykh rabochikh g. Moskvy. Redaktor: L. Levin. Moscow, Russia. 199?-, 1999: no. 1, spetsial'nyi vypusk with headline "Profsoiuz remontno- stroitel'nykh rabochikh - za semago!" 2000: spetsial'nyi vypusk with headline "Treti put'"2001: no. 3 (March), "spetsvypusk April," no. 5 (May) (Box 8)
- ANTITEZIS organ fraktsii kommunistov-demokratov oppozitsionnoi totalitarizmu partii Demokraticheskii Soiuz, tsentral'nyi region. Gl. redaktor: Griaznov, A. [s. l. :s. n. ]. 198?-, 1989: no. 1 (Box 462)
- ANTIVOENNYI VESTNIK gazeta obshchestvennoi initsiativy "Za mir v Chechne i priznanie prava Chechenskogo naroda na samoopredelenie." Sankt-Peterburg, Russia. Approx. weekly. 2002-, Redaktor: A. Skobov 2002: no. 1, no. 4-72003: no. 11, no. 13-17, no. 20, no. 22, no. 25 2004: no. 30 (Box 462)
- ANTYFASHYK infarmatsyiny antyfashystouski biuleten'. Minsk, Belarus'. 1998-, 1999: no. 1(2) (Box 462)
- APOLLON informatsionnyi biulleten'. Redaktsionnaia kollegiia: I. Koshelev, A. Kukharskii, A. Rumiantsev, K. Chistiakov. Sankt-Peterburg, Russia. 2002?-, 2002: no. 2 (Box 462)
- APOSSUM Note: APOS = Assotsiatsiia profsoiuznykh organizatsii studentov Moskvy. Moscow, Russia. 19??-, 19??: one unnumbered and undated issue titled "Est' takaia assotsiatsiia..." (Box 462)
- APREL' INFORM press-biulleten' orgkomiteta uchreditel'nogo s"ezda vsesoiuznoi assotsiatsii "Aprel'" (Pisateli v podderzhku perestroiki). Gl. redaktor: Kostiukovskii, Ia. Moscow, Russia. 1990-, 1990: no. 1-7 (March 22-April 21) (Box 8)
- APREL'SKII VETER Informatsionnyi tsentr obshchestvennogo sodeistviia perestroike. Redaktor: Kniazev, Iu. A. Riazan', RSFSR. 198?-, 1989: no. 2-4 (Box 462)
- ARABSKII MIR Note: "Izdaetsia Fondom druzhby s narodami arabskikh stran." [s. l.: s. n. ]. 19??-, 1997: July 15 1999: October 25 (Box 462)
- ARAGLAIN Moskovskaia ezhemesiachnaia gazeta. Note: Gazeta napravlennaia "na osveshchenie sobytii armianskoi diaspory v Moskve. ." Glavnyi redaktor: Sona Azarian. Moscow, Russia. Monthly. 2005-, 2005: no. 2 (Box 8)